Inventory of the Obelia "Bee" Graves Papers 1936-1945
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Obelia "Bee" Graves Papers 1936-19451937-1939
Special Collections Research Center
01/Mss. Acc. 2008.123
0.50
This collection contains letters to Obelia "Bee" Graves, from her family and friends, while she attended Winston-Salem Teachers College in Winston-Salem, North Carolina. The institution is presently known as Winston-Salem State University. Winston-Salem Teachers College was the first historically black college to grant bachelors degrees in elementary school education. The collection also includes college documents from her time at college such as report cards and her admission acceptance. The collection also contains letters from two soldiers to Bee Graves' sister, Cleonis. The soldiers served during World War II in the Philippines.
Graves, Obelia "Bee" arrangement
Administrative Information
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
The materials were acquired by Special Collections Research Center on 11/25/2008.
Biographical Note
Obelia "Bee" Graves attended Winston-Salem Teachers College in Winston-Salem, North Carolina, the first historically black college to grant bachelor degrees in elementary school education. Her family lived in Blance, North Carolina.Her parents were Vester and Sallie Graves. Further information about this individual or organization may be available in the Special Collections Research Center Wiki: http://scrc.swem.wm.edu/wiki/index.php/Obelia "Bee" Graves.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains letters to Obelia "Bee" Graves, from her family and friends, while she attended Winston-Salem Teachers College in Winston-Salem, North Carolina. The institution is presently known as Winston-Salem State University. Winston-Salem Teachers College was the first historically black college to grant bachelors degrees in elementary school education. The collection also includes college documents from her time at college such as report cards and her admission acceptance. The collection also contains letters from two soldiers to Bee Graves' sister, Cleonis. The soldiers served during World War II in the Philippines.
Additional Information
Index Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Corporate Name:
Winston-Salem State University; Winston-Salem Teachers College
Genre/Form of Material:
Correspondence; Photographs
Personal Name:
Education--North Carolina.
Topical Term:
African American women--Education.; African Americans.; Report cards; Women college students; World War, 1939-1945--Pacific Area
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Letters from Family, 1937-1939; id44200
  - Letters from Vester Graves (Father), 1937-1938; id44224 (Folder 1)
  - Letters from Sallie Graves (Mother), 1937-1939; id44225 (Folder 2)
  - Letters from Cleonis Graves (Sister), 1937; id44226 (Folder 3)
  - Letters from Melba Graves (Sister), 1937-1938; id44227 (Folder 4)
  - Letter from Ella Graves (Sister), 1938; id44743 (Folder 5)
  - Letter from Lois Long (Cousin), 1937; id44744 (Folder 6)
  - Letters from Auntie Madie, 1937; id44745 (Folder 7)
  - Letters from Uncle Henry, 1937, 1939; id44746 (Folder 8)
- Letters from Friends, 1936-1939; id44201
  - Postcards from Friends, 1936-1939; id44747 (Folder 9)
  - Letters from Female Friends, 1936; id44748 (Folder 10)
  - Letters from Elbert Swann, 1936-1938; id44749 (Folder 11)
  - Letters from Elbert Swann, undated; id44750 (Folder 12)
  - Letters from Louise Moore, 1937; id44751 (Folder 13)
  - Letters from Helen B., 1939; id44752 (Folder 14)
  - Letter from Walter (Boyfriend), 1938; id44753 (Folder 15)
  - Letters from C.L.B., Jr., 1936; id44754 (Folder 16)
  - Letters from J.B. Saunders, 1936, 1938; id44755 (Folder 17)
  - Letters from Male Friends, 1939; id44756 (Folder 18)
- Miscellaneous, 1936-1945; id44202
  - Letters from soldiers to Cleonis Graves (Sister), 1945; id44757 (Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous Items, id44758 (Folder 20)
  - College Documents, 1936-1940; id44759 (Folder 21)
  - College Documents, 1936-1940; id44761 (Folder 22)